我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help
我秘密地打击犯罪
of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但是我在时间中迷失了
But I became lost in time.
我的朋友们用尽了一切办法
It took everything in my friends' power
才把我救回来  但我们的世界
to bring me back, and in doing so
也因此出现了新的威胁
our world was opened up to new threats.
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to stop them.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
这个夸克球
The Quark Sphere,
充满了巴里特殊的遗传标记
filled with Barry's unique genetic marker,
并被编程追踪他特别的DNA
and programmed to track his specific DNA,
运用了神速力的电流
using the electrical current of the Speed Force.
一旦我们追踪到巴里  把他拉出来
Once we track Barry and we pull him out,
这个夸克球体会瞒骗神速力
the Quark Sphere will trick the Speed Force
让它以为巴里仍在那里
into thinking he's still there.
这是怎么回事
What is happening?
我们移动很快  其他人都相对静止了
We're moving so quickly that everyone else is still.
-闪电侠  -闪电侠
- Flash. - Flash.
我是你父亲的二重身
I'm your father's doppelganger.
杰西  你是极速者吗
Jesse, you're a speedster.
很酷  对不对
Yeah, it's pretty cool, right?
-杰西一切还好吗  -对
- Everything okay with Jesse? - Yes.
我花了一整个夏天给她召集了一队人马
I spent the summer assembling a support staff for her,
然而之后杰西离开了并把我踢出了小队
but then Jesse goes and kicks me off the team.
他们投票表决把我踢出去了
They took a vote. I'm out.
我现在都无家可归了
I don't even have a home to return to now.
-巴里  -爱瑞丝
- Barry... - Iris...
怎么  我是...
What--I'm...
-你在和我一起移动  --什么
- You're moving with me, okay? - What?
你现在移动得和我一样快
You're moving as fast as I am,
-就像在法院时一样  -为什么  你不是...
- like in the courtroom. - Why? Didn't you...
我没办法  我没办法
I can't. I--I can't.
-怎么了  -我没办法
- What? What's wrong? - I can't.
什么
What--
这次我救不了我们了
I can't save us this time.
闪 电 侠
第四季
第十五集
8分49秒前
准备好  巴里
Ready when you are, Barry.
-准备好了  -你认真的吗
- I'm ready! - Are you serious?
拜托  西斯科  再来一次
Come on, Cisco, just one more.
2小时前她就这么说了
She said two hours ago.
你知道不成功他不会放弃的
Look, you know he's not gonna stop until he makes it through.
拜托  你知道巴里的
Come on, you know how Barry gets.
-就再一次  -谢了
- One more. - Thank you.
开始吧
All right, here we go.
Three...
2  1
two...one.
现在
Now!
该死
Damn it!
-再来一次  -爱瑞丝
- One more. - Iris?
巴里  我们不如休息一会
Uh, Barry, look, why don't we take five?
不  除非我成功  拜托
No, not until I get this, all right? Come on.
-听着  英雄  -什么
- Listen, Miyagi... - What?
我一天都在这里  打开缺口
I've been here all day, opening breaches, all right,
所以除非你打算搓搓双手
so unless you wanna rub your hands together
给我的肩膀来个神奇的按摩
and do some magic shoulder popping...
我才不会给你按摩肩膀
I'm not rubbing your shoulder.
我就知道  我休息会儿
That's what I thought. I'm taking five.
-拜托  -我休息去了
- Hey, come on! - I'm taking five!
我
I--
我不知道我为什么没法成功
I don't understand why I can't get this.
可能是因为你忙了一整晚
Well, probably because you've been up all night.
那应该没关系
But that shouldn't matter.
巴里  桥梁在万亿分之一秒内就关闭了
Look, Barry, a bridge closes in three picoseconds.
而迪沃可以关闭得更快
DeVoe's could shut even faster.
我只是说这可能不是
Look, I'm just saying that this might not even be
抓住他的最佳计划
the best plan to catch him anyway.
这是个计划
It's a plan, you know.
我们现在只有这法子
It's the only one we have right now.
要是他用自己的力场对付你呢
Well, and what if he uses his force field against you?
你还不知道怎么从那里出来
You don't know how to get out of it yet.
不知道  爱瑞丝  但我们需要什么
I don't know, Iris, but, I mean, we need something.
对那3个巴士上的超能力者我们没有线索
We have no leads on the next three bus metas,
没办法追踪迪沃或是阻止他
no way to track DeVoe, no way to stop him.
他不可能这么聪明
I mean, he can't be this smart.
抱歉  但我们为之努力数月了
I'm sorry, but, I mean, we've been at this for months,
却一无所获
and we have nothing.
也许这才是问题
I mean, maybe that's the problem.
有时候你不得不
You know, sometimes you have to...
休息下  让答案自己浮现出来
take a breather and let the answer come to you.
-做做别的事  -比如呢
- Do something else for a bit. - Like what?
比如
Like...
先开始约会之夜
date night, for starters.
我们都没好好相处的时光
You know, we haven't had any quality time,
就我俩  自从蜜月之后
just you and me, since our honeymoon.
蜜月都被突然打断了
Which was severely cut short.
我知道我们是闪电侠小分队  但我们
I know we're the Flash, but we--
也是巴里和爱瑞丝
We're also Barry and Iris.
你说得没错
No, you're right, yeah.
我今晚去预订一个地方
All right, I'm gonna make a reservation tonight,
很浪漫的地方
someplace very romantic.
听上去太好了
Oh... Sounds perfect.
我们工作生活在一起
How is it we live together, work together,
同床共寝
sleep in the same bed together,
却怎么还感觉没有真正作为
but it stills feels like we don't spend any real time
夫妻相伴的时光
as husband and wife?
艾伦  韦斯特·艾伦  现在来表层
Allen, West Allen, cortex now!
我也不知道
I have no idea.
走吧
Let's go.
这是什么
What is this?
这是信号场
This is a signature field,
每次迪沃在口袋维度
mapping every time DeVoe's gone in and out of his layer
的贼窝中进出时  都会标记出来
in the pocket dimension.
-所有这些  -所有
- All of these? - All of them.
你怎么做到的
So, how did you do this?
其实不是我  是拉蒙
I didn't do it, actually. Ramon did.
但我所做的是
But all I did was just come up
想到一个非常复杂并有说服力的运算法则
with a really complex and eloquent algorithm
去追踪扭曲的信号
to track the warping signatures.
别这样  好吗  别谦虚
Don't do that, all right? Don't do that. Don't be modest.
-好吗  不合适  -你才不合适
- All right? It's unbecoming. - You're unbecoming.
是你希望我不合适  好吗
You wish I was unbecoming, all right?
你知道这些是迪沃吗
Do you know that these are DeVoe?
这些就是迪沃  好吗
These are DeVoe, all right?
这是马尔利泽在劳伦斯山
This is when Marlize grabbed him
从伊兹那儿带他回去
from Izzy at Lawrence Hills.
这是他在铁山监狱现身的时候
This is when he showed up at Iron Heights prison.
-这是迪沃的家  -这是市中心的
- This is DeVoe's house. - And this is the alleyway
小巷  他在这里绑架了你
in the city center, where he abducted you.
他这么做有多久了
How long has this been going on?
-可长了  -过去三年
- Oh, wait for it. - The past three years.
-3年  -迪沃精心安排一切
- Three years? - DeVoe orchestrated everything
为了得到巴士上的人
to get the people he wanted on the bus.
他计划很久了
He's been planning this a long time.
这是个计划家  和斯旺一样
We got a planner, just like Thawne.
-和斯旺一样  -怎么用这个
- Just like Thawne. - So, how do we use this?
我们现在能做的
All we can do right now
就是静待下一个标记出现
is just wait for the next marker to appear,
试着先发制人
try to get the jump on him.
还有盯好拉尔夫   用以前那套伙伴系统
That and keep an eye on Ralph, using the old buddy system.
今天有人见到他了吗
Has anyone seen Ralph today?
没有  他在楼下走来走去
No, he's downstairs, moving in.
他很紧张
He's very nervous.
-不知道为什么  -我也不知道
- I don't know why. - I don't know why either.
他是超级英雄
He's a superhero.
有超能力的人对一切都是准备好的
People with powers are ready for anything.
该死的缺口
Ah! Son of a breach!
-抱歉  -杰西
- Sorry... - Jesse.
我刚从缺口房间进来
I just came in through the breach room.
杰西  欢迎回来
Hey, Jesse, welcome back.
你来干什么
What are you-- what are you doing here?
沃利不在这里
Wally's not here.
真要道歉的话
Uh, you know, an apology cube usually works better
道歉盒通常更管用
when there's an actual apology on it.
你情绪化了
You get the sentiment.
这是什么
What's this?
那是内心活动缓冲器
That is a, uh, mental activity dampener.
给地检官塞西尔·霍尔顿用的
It's for DA Cecile Horton.
让她无法读取他人的内心
It keeps her from hearing other people's thoughts.
挺笨重
Kinda clunky.
她就是这么说的
That's what she said.
她原话就这么说的
Literally, that's what she said.
第二版好多了
The second version's more streamlined.
这是什么
And what's all this?
那些是想法  沉思
Those are thoughts, musings.
怎么去阻止迪沃的思路
How to stop DeVoe.
他现在是你的重中之重了啊
Wow, he's really in your head, isn't he?
是啊  现在很多人都是的
Yeah, a lot of people are nowadays,
多亏了你
thanks to you.
我以为你想让我过来
Look, I thought you wanted me to come here
聊聊这事
so we could talk about this.
不  我想让你不要再提起你妈妈
No, I want you to stop bringing up your mother.
我会的  一旦你接受她离开的事实
I will, once you deal with her death.
-我已经接受了  -你没有
- I have. - No, you haven't.
我接受了  她死了
Yes, I have. She died!
多年前就死了
Years ago, she died.
我没法救她
There was nothing I could do to save her.
就这样  生活还在继续
End of story. Life goes on.
是啊  除了你之外
Yeah, for everyone but you.
爸  妈走了之后  你从不谈论
Look, Dad, when Mom died, you didn't talk about it...
-这没关...  -从不提起
- There's nothing to-- - Ever.
而且自从那以后你就脾气不好
And you've been upset ever since.
惨兮兮的
You've been miserable,
而且你让身边的人也惨兮兮的
and you make everyone around you miserable.
你觉得我为什么要把你除名
I mean, why do you think I asked you to leave my team?
你的队伍里都是傻子
Your team's a bunch of idiots.
-好吧  -无意冒犯
- Okay. - No offense.
不过无所谓  我来这里是阻止迪沃
Anyway, it doesn't matter. I came here to stop DeVoe.
不  你留下来是因为迪沃
No, you stayed because of DeVoe.
没什么差别
A distinction without a difference.
爸  总有坏人需要被阻止
Dad, there is always going to be some bad guy to stop,
-或者要写出来的运算法则  -对
- or algorithm to writ.. - Yeah, that's it.
-或者需要解决的问题  -对  这就是我的问题
- Or problem to solve. - Yeah, that's my point. Exactly.
我也不想谈及她的离开
I didn't want to talk about her death,
但我还是说了
but...I did,
而这很有帮助
and it helped a lot.
相信我  你不把这心结说出来
Trust me, you are never going to be able
就没法继续好好生活
to move on with your life until you talk about this.
杰西  我做不到
Jesse! I can't!
我
I--
杰西
Look, Jesse...
你妈妈
Your mother...
你不会理解的
You'll never understand.
对  我是理解不了
Yeah. I guess I won't.
什么
What?
尖端科研实验室
卧倒
Get down!
-你还好吗  乔西  -死不了
- You all right, Jonesy? - I'll live.
给你  用力压住
Here. Put pressure on it.
救援马上到
Help's on the way.
这些人是谁  他们忽然冒出来
Who the hell are these guys? They came out of nowhere.
我不知道  但他们想要那集装箱里的东西
I don't know, but they want whatever is in that container.
在哪里
Where is that?
韦德机场的某个机棚
One of the hangars out at Waid Airfield.
我父亲说中心城警局今早在那
My dad said CCPD was escorting ARGUS there
保护天眼会做事
this morning for something.
-他在那  巴里  -对  我们得走了
- He's there, Barry. - Yeah, we gotta go.
-我们和你在那儿会合  -酷  我也去
- We'll meet you there. - Cool, I'll come too.
可以借助这个掩护
Could use the distraction.
快来  闪电侠
Come on, Flash.
伙计们  七名警官和天眼会特工被放倒了
Guys, seven officers and ARGUS agents down.
他们刚刚炸开了天眼会运输的集装箱
They just blew open the ARGUS transport container.
机棚西侧  一名武装分子进去了
West side of the hangar. One armed assailant inside.
明白
Got it!
比对系统
快点
Come on.
可以开始了
It's ready.
趴下
Stay down!
走  走  走
Move! Move, move!
只剩下你和我们了
Just you and us now.
大家干得好
Nice work, everyone.
结束了
It's over.
为了中城的所有人
For all of Central City.
引爆核弹
激活
不
No...
巴里
Barry...
我们太晚了
We're too late.
-那是个核弹  -我知道
- Oh, that's a nuclear bomb. - I know.
它的核心到临界状态了
And its core has already gone critical.
我知道
I know.
我们一慢下来  就完了
The second we slow down, it's over.
我知道  说这个没用
I know. That's not helping.
我们还有多少时间
Well, how long do you think we have?
我们必须不停地移动
We just have to keep moving
直到我们找出办法解决它
till we figure out a way to stop it.
我们可以把它带到巴德兰斯
Oka--okay, we could run it to the Badlands.
如果我们跑那么远  会加速反应
No, if we run that long, it'll speed up the reaction.
没法在爆炸前把它移出城市
We won't make it outside the city before it explodes.
我们不可能把所有人移出城市
Well, we can't run everyone outside the city.
我知道
I know.
我们说的是几十万人
We're talking hundreds of thousands of people.
只要人数比我们两个人多
I mean, if there were more than just the two of us,
时间就不够
there's not enough time.
等等  对了
Wait, that's it.
-杰伊·加里克  -他怎么了
- Jay Garrick. - What about him?
他可能知道要怎么做
Uh, he might know what to do.
去地球三  找他来
Go to Earth-3, get him,
尽快把他带回来
bring him back here as fast as you can, okay?
我现在需要你
I need you right now, man.
这是怎么了
Whoa, what is going on?
你在和我一起以超级速度移动
You're moving with me at super-speed.
什么
What?
你跑的时候就是这个感觉吗
Is this what it looks like when you run?
差不多
More or less.
我得说这有点平淡无奇啊
I have to say, it's a little uneventful.
跟我来
Hey...come with me.
这就是我们的约柜了
I'm guessing this is our Ark of the Covenant.
确实和那有点像
Something like that, yeah.
那肯定能溶了你的脸
Yeah, that will definitely melt your face.
电影《夺宝奇兵》中打开约柜的纳粹被溶掉了脸
看着像一台实验用核裂变仪器
That...that looks like an experimental fission engine,
氘同位素
deuterium isotopes.
那这个就是惯性约束柜了
That would make this an inertial confinement cage
可以阻断辐射
to stop the radiation.
但是只要有足够的压力
But with enough pressure,
里面的同位素就会分裂
the isotopes inside, they split,
会产生热  产生光
they produce heat, they produce light.
先是蓝色
It starts out blue,
然后是黄色  接着是紫色
turns yellow, turns purple,
然后我们就完了
and then it's game over.
拜托告诉我有办法逆转它
Just please tell me there's a way we can undo it.
我们已经错过可逆转时间了
I think we're way past that point.
-我们得做点什么  -我...
- We have to do something. - I--
要是  要是我把它弄到荒废的地球上
what if--what if I breach it to a dead Earth,
-就像我处理辐射那样  -当然可以
- like I did with Fallout? - Of course, yeah.
好主意  去做吧
That's a great idea. All right, do it.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我可能透支了
I think I might be all breached out.
我不知道
I-I don't know,
可能我今天打开缺口太多次了
I think I breached one too many times today.
不  不是因为这个
No, that's not it.
打开缺口本质上是折叠时空
A breach is a folding of space-time, right,
所以当我们高速移动
so when we're moving this fast, we--
当我们高速移动  当我们身处闪电时间
When we're moving this fast, when we're moving in Flashtime,
我们没有形成一个缺口所必要的
then we don't have the time necessary
-足够的时间  -没错
- for a breach to form. - Exactly.
这就意味着我不能
Then that means I can't...
That means I--I can't...
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不是极速者
You're not a speedster.
你的身体没法长期承受高速移动
Your body can't handle moving this fast very long.
我得放开你  好吗
I gotta let go, all right?
过来
Come here.
等等  问哈里
Wait...ask Harry.
他会知道的
He'll know.
好吧
All right.
我希望如此
I hope so.
艾伦
A--Allen...
-威尔斯  -你碰我干嘛
- Wells, hey... - Uh, why are you touching me?
-这  -听着
- Th-- - Listen...
我是不是在
Am I in-- am I in...
没错  你在闪电时间中
Yes, you're in Fla-- you're in Flashtime, yes.
闪电时间  闪电时间是什么
Flashtime? What is Flashtime?
-我没...  -西斯科刚想出这个词
- I didn't-- - Cisco just came up with it.
在你和我共享闪电时间之前你和拉蒙试过了
Wait, you did this with Ramon before you did this with me?
-我们没时间了  -那个警报
- Hey, we don't have time! - Hey, listen, the alarm--
我们去处理的那个警报是天眼会的运输机
Yes, the alarm that we left for was an ARGUS transport.
-里面有个核裂变仪器  -它爆炸了
- It had a fission engine in it. - And it exploded?
这就是我在闪电时...
That's why I'm in this Flashti--
等等  杰西  杰西在哪
wait...Jesse. Where's Jesse?
她很好  她离开了  她去了
She's--no, she's fine. She left. She went to--
艾伦  这很好
Okay, Allen, that's great,
要是这个城市要炸了
because if this city's gonna explode,
你得尽量把她送远一点
you need to send her as far away from here as possible...
不  她去了地球三去找杰伊·加里克
No, listen--listen, she went to Earth-3 to get Jay Garrick.
-她会回来  -对  我们需要他的帮助
- She's coming back? - Yes, we need his help.
艾伦  不  我们不能让她
Allen, no, no, no, no, we cannot let her--
现在我需要你得帮助
Hey! Right now, I need your help, okay?
-我要怎么才能阻止核反应  -你阻止不了
- How do I stop the reaction? - You can't stop this.
你什么意思  那我要做什么
What do you mean? Then what do I do?
你不能  你得把它送走
You can't--you have to send it away from here.
-我送不走  我们试了  -让拉蒙打开
- Well, I can't. We tried... - Open--have Ramon open a--
-西斯科做不到  西斯科打不开缺口
- Cisco can't--he can't. Cisco can't open a breach.
-他做不到  -因为没有时间
- He can't. - 'Cause there's no time.
-没错  -但是你可以
- Exactly. - But you can.
-你说什么  -艾伦  你可以
- What do you mean? - Allen, you can.
-我做不到  -听我说
- No, I can't. - Listen to me--
-你说什么呢  -艾伦  听我说
- What are you talking about? - Allen, listen to me,
时空缺口和到神速力的传送门
space-time breaches and the portal to the Speed Force
不是同一原理
operate under different physics.
你打开一个通往神速力的传送门
You open a portal to the Speed Force.
把核弹扔进去
You send it there.
它会对神速力有什么影响
What will it do to the Speed Force?
-什么  我为什么变虚弱了  -威尔斯
- What is--why am I weak? - Wells...
-威尔斯  -是速度
- I know. Wells, hey--hey... - It's the speed--the--
听我说  爆炸会
Listen to me, will an explosion--
-速度在影响我  -我知道
- The speed's affecting me. - I know.
爆炸会对神速力有什么大影响吗
Will an explosion that big affect the Speed Force?
我不  这么认为
I don't...think so.
什么  你这么说什么意思
What? What do you mean you don't think so?
-我不知道  -威尔斯  看着我
- I don't know. - Wells, hey, look at me--
怎么回事
What the heck?
-把她送出去  -我会  努力
- Get her out of here. - I'm gonna--I'll try--
-艾伦  -好了
- Allen--Allen... - All right.
-你是怎么做到的  -我不确定
- How'd you do that? - Um, I'm not sure.
自从我从神速力里出来
I've--I've been able to do it
就能这么做了
ever since I came out of the Speed Force.
-这个新技能不错啊  -现在...
- That's a hell of a new trick. - Look, right now--
我知道  杰西给我看了核炸弹
I know. Jesse showed me the nuke.
-我们有大麻烦了  孩子  -我不知道
- We're in trouble, kid. - Well, I don't know.
威尔斯说他有个主意可能有用
Wells has an idea that he thinks might work.
是吗  是什么
Yeah? What is it?
我们把炸弹送到神速力里
We send the bomb into the Speed Force,
让它在那里引爆
let it detonate in there.
-你不能这样  -你什么意思  为什么
- Like hell you will. - What do you mean? Why not?
因为闪电侠  你要是这么做
Because, Flash, if you do that,
我们可能永远失去神速力
we may lose the Speed Force forever.
什么叫我们都会丧失神速力
What do you mean we might lose the Speed Force?
这种规模的爆炸可能彻底摧毁它
An explosion that size could destroy it completely.
如果它被毁了
If that were to happen,
广袤时空中的每个极速者
every speedster across space and time
都会立即丧失他们的速度
would lose access to their speed instantly.
每个极速者
Every speedster?
即便这能够摆脱斯旺
Even if it got rid of Thawne
和多元宇宙中其他邪恶的极速者
and every other evil speedster in the multiverse,
你也不能这么做
you cannot do this.
我不会让你这么做
I won't let you.
对不起  杰伊
Well, I'm sorry, Jay,
如果这是拯救这座城市里所有人的唯一方法
if this is the only way to save everyone in the city,
我必须这么做
I have to.
巴里  听我说
Barry, listen to me...
哈里对神速力一无所知
Harry didn't know anything about the Speed Force, okay?
我们都不真正了解它
None of us really do.
神速力并不只是包括速度
And this isn't just about speed.
你在谈论摧毁多元宇宙中的
You're talking about destroying
一个核心元素
an essential element of the multiverse.
没人知道后果如何
Nobody knows what the consequences will be.
你在那里的时间比我久
You were trapped in there longer than I was.
-如果有人可以理  -然后呢  杰伊
- If anyone can underst-- - Then what, Jay?
你有什么主意
What's your idea?
我爸还有其他主意吗
I mean, did my dad have any other ideas?
没有  但是我们没法谈太长时间
No...but we couldn't talk for very long.
杰伊  抱歉  我只是...
Jay, I'm sorry, I just--
不  没事的孩子  我懂
No, it's all right, kid. I get it.
好了  从头再来
All right, back to basics.
在核裂变中
In nuclear fission,
原子分裂释放中子引发的连锁反应
enormous energy is created by a chain reaction of atoms
释放出巨大的能量
splitting and releasing neutrons.
想要逆转基本不可能
It's nearly impossible to reverse this process,
但是  理论上
but, theoretically...
你可以恢复稳定性
you could restore stability.
怎么做
How?
有一个办法是通过核聚变
One way is to offset the loss of mass
-来抵消损失的质量  -真棒
- by nuclear fusion. - Great.
你这里有什么类似的机器
You have some sort of machine lying around here
能产生这么大的能量吗
that could generate that kind of energy?
我们没有
No, we don't.
但另一个方法  以我们目前的困境来看
But the other way, considering our predicament,
更可行一些
seems more promising.
什么方法
Which is what?
让它冷却
Cooling it down.
我们得快点
We need to hurry.
闪电侠  这里这么多都冻住的人
I see all these frozen people around me, Flash,
这一次可不是我的错哦
and this time, it's not my fault.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
这次是三个人了  发生了什么
Three of you now. What's going on?
-集装箱里的货物  -是个核弹
- The cargo in this container. - It's a nuclear bomb.
是啊  而且快炸了
Yeah, and it went kaboom.
-真好  -过来
- Dandy. - Come here.
这里跟烤箱似的
Whoo, it's toasty in here.
我们需要你把它冷却
We need you to cool it down.
你们想让我冷却一个已经
You want me to cool down a nuclear reaction
到临界点的核子反应
that's already gone critical?
你们是认真的啊
You're serious?
快点  谢谢  冰霜女士
Quickly, please, Ms. Frost.
好吧  试一下好了
All right, let's give it a whirl.
和我预期的不太一样
Didn't go quite how I expected.
再试试
Tr--try again.
不好...
Oh, no...
所以这就是热的感觉吗
Huh, so that's what heat feels like.
你热起来了
You're burning up.
来吧
Come on.
好了  没事的
All right, it's okay.
好了
All right.
我得放开你了  好吗
I have to let you go, all right?
巴里
Barry?
别让凯特琳死了
Don't let Caity die.
好
Okay.
现在怎么办
Now what?
看起来咱们还是得去找个核聚变机器
Guess we have to find that fusion machine after all.
-等一下  -怎么
- Wait a second... - What?
如果我们当那机器呢
What if we're the machine?
怎么说
How so?
你说我们可以通过核聚变的能量
Well, you said that we could offset the energy of the bomb
来抵消炸弹的能量
with the energy from nuclear fusion.
理论上是这样
Theoretically.
对  那个箱子里的反应释放出了
Right, and the reaction in that container's giving off,
我不知道  三百万吨的能量吗
I don't know, 3 million tons of energy?
-大概如此  -所以  三百万吨的能量
- Give or take. - So, 3 megatons of energy,
那是三十亿焦耳
that's 3 billion joules.
每道闪点大概在十亿焦耳左右  所以...
Each lightning bolt gives off roughly 1 billion joules, so...
只要我们一同
So if we all throw a lightning bolt
-扔出闪电的话  -很可能就足够了
- at the same time... - It could be enough.
足够了  会有用的  咱们开始吧
That's enough. That'll work. Let's do it.
杰伊
Jay!
我有点...
I'm--
我没坚持过这么久
I'm not used to going this long.
没事的
Hey, hey, hey, it's okay.
-该死的腿  -没事的
- Damn legs... - It's all right.
不像以前那么有用了
Don't work like they once did.
没事的
It's okay.
我是没法做到了  闪电侠
I'm not gonna be able to finish this one, Flash.
-真抱歉  -休息吧
- I'm sorry. - Just rest.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so...sorry.
巴里  只有咱俩没法产生足够的电能
Barry, the two of us can't produce enough lightning power
来抵消炸弹的能量
to offset the energy from that bomb.
即便全速状态也不行  况且我们也不在
I mean, even if we had full speed, which we don't,
最起码我不是
at least I don't.
我们得把它送到神速力中去
We have to send it into the Speed Force.
你听到杰伊怎么说的了
You--you heard what Jay said.
哈里说会没事的
And Harry said it'd be fine.
不  他说他认为会没事
No, he said he thinks it would be fine.
巴里  我爸爸从不说认为  他说知道
Barry, my dad never thinks anything, he knows.
杰伊说的对  我们不能这么做
Jay was right, we can't do it.
该死
Damn it!
好吧  如果...
Okay, what if--
我不知道  如果我们穿越时间
I don't know, what if we run back in time
阻止这个炸弹启动呢
and stop this bomb from ever going off?
不行  杰西  我们不能这么做
No, Jesse, we can't do that.
这大概是我们唯一的选择了
Yeah, well, it's kind of our only option.
这不是选择之一
It's not an option.
即便能拯救这个城市和所有人吗
Even if it saves the city and everyone in it?
这救不了他们  好吗
It's not saving them, okay?
一旦你改变了时间线
The second you alter the timeline,
所有事物都会变  尤其是你所爱的人
everything changes, especially the people you love.
相信我  我是经历过这苦难的
Trust me. I learned that the hard way.
也许来个新版本的爸爸
Yeah, well, maybe a new version of my dad
不是世上最糟的事
isn't the worst thing in the world.
杰西  不管你们俩有什么纠葛
Look, Jesse, whatever problems you two have,
它们不可能通过
they're not gonna get solved
逼他去做他不想做的事而解决
by forcing him to do something he doesn't want to.
他需要自己做出决定
He has to make that decision.
天啊
Oh, God.
反应堆的爆发已经进入最后阶段了
The reaction's combustion's reached its final phase.
我想咱们是慢下来了
I think we're slowing down.
所以其他一切开始加速了
So everything else is speeding up.
巴里  我想不出办法了
Barry, I don't have any more ideas.
我也是
Me either.
我不知道我还能跑多久
I don't know how much longer I can run.
好了  你得离开这里
All right, you have to get out of here.
用你剩下的速度回到地球二去
Use the speed you have left to get back to Earth-2.
-你爸爸想让你离开  -我听到了
- Your dad wanted you to leave. - Yeah, I heard.
这是要保证你的安全  杰西
So you'd be safe, Jesse.
他爱你  好吗
He loves you, all right?
胜过一切
More than anything.
-走吧  -不行  我不能...
- Go. - No, I can't just--
走吧
Go.
对不起
I'm sorry.
天啊
Oh, God.
我真希望能在你还能听到的时候告诉你
I wish I could tell you this while you could still hear me,
但是
but...
我知道妈妈让你有多幸福
I know how happy Mom made you
还有现在她不在之后你有多伤心
and how sad you are now that she's gone.
但我就是  不知道你为什么不想谈一谈
But I just--I don't know why you won't talk about it.
我知道也许我不需要
I know maybe I don't need to,
但是...
but...
我只是想让你再次幸福
I just want you to be happy again.
我想要的只有这个
That's all I've ever wanted.
我得想出点办法来
I've got to think of something.
快啊
Oh, come on.
巴里  爱瑞丝
Barry... Iris...
怎么  我是...
What--I'm...
你移动的速度和我一样快
You're moving as fast as I am...
-什么  -就像是在法庭时一样
- What? - Like in the courtroom.
-为什么  你不是...  -我没办法
- Why? Why? Didn't you... - I can't...
-我的天  什么  -我没办法
- Oh, my God, what? - I can't.
什么
Uh, what?
这次我没办法救我们了
I can't save us this time.
你不能救我们是什么意思
What do you mean, you can't save us?
-有个炸弹  -什么
- There's a bomb... - What?
一个核弹  已经炸了
A nuke, it's already gone off.
-我没法阻止它  -肯定会有办法的
- I can't stop it. - Wait--but there's a way.
你肯定能想到办法的  巴里
There's gotta be something that you can do, Barry.
不行  我们试了  我们试了所有办法
No, listen, I tried. We tried everything.
我们试了闪电  我们试了冷却
We tried lightning, we tried cooling it down,
扔到没生命的地球上
reaching into a dead earth,
但是都没有起作用
but there's nothing that will work.
-我不知道该怎么办  -好吧
- I don't know what to do. - Okay.
我只要一停下来  它就会...
Hey, as soon as I stop, it's gonna--
我知道  我知道  没事的
I know. I know. Hey--hey, it's okay.
我不知道还能支撑多久
I don't know how much longer I can hold out.
-我好累  -没事的
- I'm so tired. - Okay.
没事的  巴里
It's okay, Barry.
天啊  你热的要死
Oh, my God, you're burning up.
我已经这样有段时间了
I've been at this for a while...
-好吧  -对我来说
- Okay. - For me.
看着我  看着我
Hey--hey, look at me, look at me...
-真对不起  -不  别道歉
- I'm sorry. - No, don't be sorry.
-看着我  和我在一起  -真对不起
- Look at me. Be here with me. - I'm sorry.
好了
Okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这与我所想的
This isn't exactly
单独相处时间不太一样  不过
the quality time I was imagining, but...
也挺棒的
It's still nice.
和你在的每一时刻  巴里  都很棒
Every moment with you, Barry, has always been nice.
每一刻
Every moment.
你就是我的避雷针  爱瑞丝
You're my lightning rod, Iris.
怎么了
What?
你说你试过闪电  怎么用的
You said you tried to use lightning. How?
我们试过了  没有用
We tried. It--it didn't work.
如果有足够的能量
If it was powerful enough,
就可以融合分裂的原子
it could've fused the split atoms,
可以消除炸弹的效果
it could've negated the effects of the bomb,
但我一个人做不到
but I can't do it alone.
我无法产出那么大的能量
I can't generate that kind of energy.
对  你不能
No, you can't...
但是神速力可以
but the Speed Force can.
什么
What?
当你进入神速力时
When you went into the Speed Force,
由风暴里打出的闪电
the--the lightning from the storm...
其中一道应该就足够了
One of those bullets would be more than enough,
但是我做不到
but I--I can't.
我怎么给它引出来  我做不到
How--how could I draw that out? I can't.
听着  当我们救出你时
No, listen, when we freed you,
西斯科和凯瑟琳  他们用夸克球体
Cisco and Caitlin, they used a Quark Sphere
编入你的遗传标记
programmed with your genetic marker
来欺骗神速力  让它认为
to trick the Speed Force into thinking
你依然在里边
that you were still in there.
我只需要拿到那球体
I just need to get that sphere,
然后风暴就会追我
and the storm will chase me.
就像你说的
It's like you said,
一个带出闪电的避雷针
a lightning rod to bring out the lightning.
-一定要回到我身边  -以我最快的速度
- Come back to me. - As fast as I can.
来吧
Here we go.
杰西
Jesse?
你在这里
You're here.
我在这里
I'm here.
巴里
Barry?
Barry!
巴里
闪电侠
Flash!
Flash?
我们死了吗
Are we dead?
没有
No.
幸好
That's good.
今天我向你们展示了城市陷落多么容易
Today, I showed you how easy a city can fall.
记住我的话
Mark my words,
核能只会带给这个世界毁灭
nuclear power will bring only destruction to the world.
你们会再次见到
You'll see it again,
那时
and when you do,
你们都会记得我的名字  维罗妮卡·戴尔
you'll all remember the name, Veronica Dale,
并完全理解我的行为
and fully understand my actions.
伊甸队
Eden Corps! Eden Corps!
伊甸...
Eden Co--
我觉得她说的"伊甸队"
I feel like she's saying, "Eden Corps."
指的是炸了所有人
As in blasting everybody
返回伊甸园的开始
back to the days of the Garden of Eden.
这本是在城市陷落后广播
This was to air after the city fell.
在她的公寓找到了宣言
Found her manifesto at her apartment.
环保行动主义者成为动物解放者
Environmental activist turned animal liberator
变成恐怖分子  变得疯疯癫癫
- turned domestic terrorist. - Turned cray-cray.
她怎么找到天眼会的空投的
How did she find out about the ARGUS drop anyway?
一定有人告诉了她
Somebody must have tipped her off.
-迪沃  -但是为什么他还是她
- DeVoe. - But why would he, or she--
无论谁要炸了全城呢
whoever--why blow up the whole city?
为什么要杀了这里所有人
Why kill nearly everyone here?
也许这种疯狂无法解释
Maybe there is no method to the madness.
很有趣  和往常一样
Well, this was fun, as usual,
但也是时候老红色彗星
but it's time for the ol' Crimson Comet
回家了
to head back home.
谢谢你的帮助  杰伊
Thanks for your help, Jay.
如果不是因为你俩和杰西
Yeah, if it wasn't for you two and Jesse,
现在新闻里说的就是完全另一码事了
it'd be a completely different story in the news right now.
你也是重要一部分  爱瑞丝
You were a big part of that, Iris.
名至实归
Credit where credit's due.
正是我想说的
My sentiments exactly.
你回到家需要休息
So, when you get home, you need to rest.
你的血糖值很低
Your glucose levels are pretty low.
谢谢  等我回去
Thanks. When I get back,
我会什么都不做只休息
I think I'll be doing nothing but getting rest.
意思是
Meaning?
我已经在这个英雄游戏中很久了
I've been at this hero game a long time,
实在很久了
a long, long time,
过了今天
and after today,
我想试试新的东西
I'm thinking about trying my hand at something new.
比如说
Like what?
首先  训练某人接班
For starters, training someone to take over.
你的地球上有另一个闪电侠
There's another Flash on your earth?
会有的
There will be...
在我训练她之后
soon as I'm done training her.
她
Her?
你认为神速力没事了吗
Well, do you think we're good with the Speed Force?
如果不是  我们很快会知道
Well, if not, we'll find out soon enough.
幸会  闪电侠
Always a pleasure, Flash.
幸会
Always.
你也需要休息  先生
So, you need to rest as well, Mister.
没有跑  没有闪电侠
No running, no Flash.
-你的身体过负  -我很好
- Your system is taxed. - I'm good.
会好的  不是现在
You will be, but you'u' not yet.
对的  有什么情况  我们处理
That's right. Anything comes up, we got it.
爱瑞丝  确保这人休息
Iris, make sure this man rests.
没问题
I'm on it.
-漫长一天  -是的
- Long day. - Yes, it was.
当我在闪电时间时
You know, I realized a couple of things
-我意识到几件事情  -什么事
- when I was in Flashtime. - Yeah, what's that?
我足够快抓住迪沃
Well...I'm more than fast enough to catch DeVoe.
只需知道他什么时候
We just need to know when he's coming out of
从口袋维度出来
the pocket dimension sooner.
我们会想出办法的
Yeah. We'll figure that out.
别的事呢
What's the other thing?
你说得对  要喘口气
You were right about taking a breather.
就和你一起
Just...A moment with you,
再变回普通
being grounded again,
所有事都更清晰了
everything becomes more clear.
挪一挪
Scooch over.
抱歉没了约会之夜
I'm sorry about date night.
不用
Don't be.
能量棒和运动裤
PowerBars and sweatpants, it's...
就是我要的所有
all I really need.
我要走了
Uh, this is my exit.
你...
Your--oh...
是的
Right.
是
Yeah.
杰西
Jesse...
之所以我不能谈论...
the reason that I can't talk about--
没有关系
You know what, it's--it's okay.
-你不用解释  -我不用
- You don't have to explain it. - I don't--I don't?
我以为这是你需要的
I thought that's what you wanted.
我想让你承认
I don't know, I thought making you confront
你失去妈妈的所有情绪
all the emotions that you have with losing Mom
会帮你走出来
would help you move on...
再次快乐
And be happy again.
但我不能决定你何时准备好这么做
But I can't decide when you're ready to do that,
等你准备好  抱歉如果我...
only you can, so I'm--I'm sorry if--
不要道歉  没有关系
No, don't be sorry. It's okay.
我确实想让你知道
I do want you to know, though,
如果时间合适
if the time comes and...
你想谈了
you wanna talk about it,
我会在
I'm here.
实际上
Actually...if that's the case,
你何不等会儿再走
why don't you stick around for a little bit longer?
你想现在谈吗
What, you wanna talk now?
不  我想让你听
No...I'd like you to listen.
请坐
Have a seat.
我要把它固定在你的前额
I'm going to fix this to your forehead.
-是什么  -改进新型
- What is that? - It's the streamlined version
地检官塞西尔·霍尔的内心活动缓冲器
of DA Cecile Horton's mental activity dampener.
-好升级  -谢谢
- Nice upgrade. - Thank you.
但我以为这是
- But I thought this was, uh,
为了阻挡别人的想法
supposed to block out people's thoughts?
不再是了
Not anymore.
现在
Now...
它能让你听到他们
it allows you to hear them.
你母亲
Your mother...
我不知道怎么...
I don't know-- I don't know how--I don't--
当你有像我和
You see, when you have a love--
你母亲
had a love...
所拥有的爱时
Like your mother and I had,
你失去那样的爱
and you lose that love...
无论如何
Anyway, um...
这会帮你理解
Maybe this will help you understand
为什么对我来说这么难
why it's been so hard for me.
因为在浩瀚的夜空中
Because in the vast night sky,
你是我看到的唯一的星星
you are the only star I see.
妈妈
Mom.
她是个奇迹
She's a miracle.
杰西
Jesse.
她和我一样
She's just like me.
宝贝  过来
Sweetie, come here.
和我一起
Be with me.
谢谢  阿里
Thank you, Ally.
-所以呢  -所以呢
- So... - So?
杰西走的时候看起来好多了
Jesse seemed better when she left.
你也是
So do you.
你俩好好谈了吗
Did you guys have a nice talk?
实际上
Well, it was actually
不是谈而是聆听
more of a listening session than a talk,
我们很好  我俩都是
but we're good, yeah, both of us.
很好  哈里
That's good, Harry.
你呢
Yeah, and what about you?
-什么  -说吧
- What? - Come on.
我了解你  你心里有事
I know you well enough to know that something's on your mind.
什么
What is it?
是冰霜杀手
It's...Killer Frost.
冰霜杀手怎么了
What about Killer Frost?
我对她说的话做的事一无所知
I don't know anything that she says or does.
有这样一个你毫无了解的人
It's scary and alarming
住在你的身体里
to have this person that you know nothing about
让我害怕又恐惧
living inside of you.
但是第一次
But for the first time,
我记得她做了什么
I remember what she did.
你记得什么
What do you remember?
巴里带她进入闪电时间
Barry taking her into Flashtime,
试图冷冻炸弹
trying to freeze the bomb...
然后
And...
冰霜杀手担心
Killer Frost being...worried.
担心什么  怕死吗
Worried about...what? About dying?
担心我
About me.
有趣
Interesting.
我很抱歉
Oh, my gosh, I'm so sorry.
我不是故意洒的
I didn't mean to drop that.
-从我手中滑掉了  -没关系
- It just slipped out of my hands. - That's okay.
天啊  我第一次
Oh, gosh, my first...
冰霜杀手  我都毁了
Killer Frost, and I go and ruin it.
-老毛病  -那不是
- Typical--typical me. - That's not....
没关系  不用担心
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
我紧张时变得笨手笨脚
I just get so clumsy when I'm nervous.
你紧张什么呢
What are you nervous about?
我在这里约了人
Um, I'm--I'm supposed to be meeting some people here
第一次我这么紧张发抖
for the first time, and I've got the jitters,
也是这个地方的名字
which... Is what this place is called.
是的
Hey! It is.
-名字很合适  不觉得吗  -同意
- Apt name, don't you think? - I do.
有趣  你紧张
It's funny, you know, you get nervous,
到吉特斯咖啡  买了咖啡
you get the Jitters, you go for coffee,
咖啡因有兴奋剂作用
and the caffeine acts as a stimulant,
让你发抖  也可以被叫做
which makes you shaky, which could also be known as...
- 吉特斯[发抖]  -正是
- The jitters. - Exactly.
明白
Okay, ri--I get it.
我们要走了
We're gonna go.
我真的很抱歉
Um, I'm really very, very sorry.
不用担心  祝你好运
Don't worry about it. Good luck with your meeting.
希望顺利  -多谢
- I hope it goes well. - Thanks.
是顺利
It did.